Finding Aid for the Eduardo Rosenzvaig Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Eduardo Rosenzvaig Papers
undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0372
1.67 linear feet
Biography of Quino & Caloi
Quino
Quino was born Joaquin Salvador, an Argentinean cartoonist born in the province of Mendoza, Argentina in 1932. Quino began drawing cartoons when he was 14 but stopped for a small period of time when he was in the military. After his hiatus, he went to Buenos Aires, Argentina and began showing his material. He was first published in 1954 by a periodical titled Esto Es. In 1964 “Mafalda” was born, one of Quinos’ most famous cartoons. Quino’s cartoons are still published mostly throughout Central America and Europe. Quino is a known satirist and his cartoons have an undertone of frustration, a pattern which he claims to have been unintentional. He continues to publish cartoons in the Clarin, an Argentinean magazine.
Caloi
Caloi, born Carlos Loiseau, is an Argentinean cartoonist born in Salta, Argentina in 1948. Caloi was first published in 1966 by a magazine called Tia Vicente. In 1973, “Clemente” was born, one of his most successful caricatures. “Clemente” is still circulated in Clarin and Viva, two successful Latin-American publications. Calois’ cartoons are published worldwide in magazines, books and newspapers. He has won numerous awards and aside from being the creator of “Clemente,” he also directs television programs.
Scope and Contents
The following material is a collection of comics from the cartoonists: Quino and Caloi. As a whole, the collection is composed of copies of their artwork and newspaper clippings. There is also an interview of Quino from the magazine Clarin and a clipping about Al Hirschfeld accompanied with some of his work.
- Quino, 1981-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Quino, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Quino, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Caloi, April 1981-September 1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Caloi, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Caloi, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Caloi, January 1985-March 1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Caloi, May 1985-December 1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Caloi, February 1986-April 1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Caloi, May 1986-August 1986 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Caloi, September 1986-December 1986 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Caloi, 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Caloi, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Al Hirschfeld, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 35)